<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog — Adam Vigneaux</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/</link><description>Recent content on Blog — Adam Vigneaux</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.adamvig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What I Don't Self-Host</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/what-i-dont-self-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/what-i-dont-self-host/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a follow-up to &lt;a href="https://blog.adamvig.com/what-i-self-host/">What I Self-Host&lt;/a>, here are a few things I intentionally do not self-host.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="password-manager">Password manager&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/">Bitwarden&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/pricing/">Premium&lt;/a> for $10/year instead of self-hosting &lt;a href="https://github.com/dani-garcia/vaultwarden">vaultwarden&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/help/install-and-deploy-unified-beta/">the official Bitwarden server&lt;/a>. I don&amp;rsquo;t trust myself with the security of my own vault and I can&amp;rsquo;t tolerate any downtime caused by home power/internet outages or my own server management mistakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="email">Email&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="https://www.fastmail.com/">Fastmail&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.fastmail.com/pricing/">Standard&lt;/a>, which is $152/year for my wife and I, for email, contacts, and calendars. I would feel comfortable using something like Nextcloud for contacts and calendars, but I don&amp;rsquo;t trust myself with the security, privacy, or stability of hosting email for my family, and I assume that Fastmail&amp;rsquo;s spam filtering is more trustworthy than most open source options.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="media-streaming">Media streaming&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t self-host a media server, like Plex or Jellyfin, because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a local media collection at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dns">DNS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="https://nextdns.io/">NextDNS&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://nextdns.io/pricing">Pro&lt;/a> for $20/year instead of self-hosting &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-hole&lt;/a> because I don&amp;rsquo;t trust myself to achieve the reliability and speed of a hosted service.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="budgeting">Budgeting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="https://www.ynab.com/">YNAB&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.ynab.com/">$100/year&lt;/a> because I doubt that there are self-hosted options with such reliable transaction importing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I Self-Host</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/what-i-self-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/what-i-self-host/</guid><description>&lt;p>I &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-hosting_(web_services)">self-host&lt;/a> several applications and websites on my home server:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/">Home Assistant&lt;/a> for home automation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.authelia.com/">Authelia&lt;/a> for authentication in front of my homemade web applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://deluge-torrent.org/">Deluge&lt;/a> for torrents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ddclient.net/">ddclient&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_DNS">dynamic DNS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://esphome.io/">ESPHome&lt;/a> Dashboard for flashing smart home devices that run ESPHome&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/sissbruecker/linkding">Linkding&lt;/a> for bookmarks (like Pinboard)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://miniflux.app/">Miniflux&lt;/a> for RSS feeds (like Feedly)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My personal websites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/">Nextcloud&lt;/a> for file storage (like Google Drive) and photo backup (like Google Photos)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wallabag.org/">Wallabag&lt;/a> for read-it-later (like Pocket or Instapaper)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Input Lists and Stage Diagrams</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/inputliststagediagram/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/inputliststagediagram/</guid><description>&lt;p>The most important communication that happens ahead of a musical event is in the form of a technical rider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The technical rider includes specifications for sound, lighting, video, and backline equipment. The key parts of the rider are the input list, which describes all of the audio inputs the band will need, and the stage diagram, which shows the layout of the instruments and performers on stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An input list must contain three pieces of information for each input:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>channel number&lt;/li>
&lt;li>instrument name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>microphone/direct box type&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If microphone or direct box type is unknown, leave it blank. This is an example input list:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Channel&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Instrument&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Input&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Lead Vocal&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SM 58&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Bkg Vocal&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SM 58&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electric Guitar&lt;/td>
&lt;td>e609 (isolation)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Keyboard Left&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DI&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Keyboard Right&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DI&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Bass Amp&lt;/td>
&lt;td>BETA 52a&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Kick&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Audix D6&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Snare&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SM 57&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Drum Side&lt;/td>
&lt;td>KSM 32&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>10&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Drum Top&lt;/td>
&lt;td>KSM 32&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Click&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DI&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>12&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Tracks Left&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DI&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>13&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Tracks Right&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DI&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>A stage diagram must at least contain the placement of all musicians and instruments. It can be made more helpful by adding placement of microphones, direct boxes, and guitar stands; but most of that information can be extrapolated from the arrangement of the band.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create a more complex stage diagram for situations where the tech should not have any creative input. Create a barebones stage diagram for situations where the tech is experienced and should provide creative input.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a complex example of a stage diagram:&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="example-complex-stage-diagram.png">
&lt;img src="example-complex-stage-diagram.png" alt="Example Complex Stage Diagram" />
&lt;/a>
&lt;p>The above example includes detailed placement information for everything including Aviom personal mixers. This type of stage diagram is useful when the band works closely with the technical team; it can help turn setup into a simple mechanical process by getting all of the decision-making out of the way in advance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a simpler example of a stage diagram:&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="example-simple-stage-diagram.png">
&lt;img src="example-simple-stage-diagram.png" alt="Example Simple Stage Diagram" />
&lt;/a>
&lt;p>When creating a stage diagram, it is helpful to keep the following guidelines in mind:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>arrange vocalists in order from left to right&lt;/li>
&lt;li>maintain a line of sight between drums, bass, and other rhythm instruments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>spread the band out across all available stage space&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Skill, Not Talent</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/skillnottalent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/skillnottalent/</guid><description>&lt;p>Talent is natural aptitude.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skill is hard-earned knowledge and experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calling a person talented implies that they were born with the
abilities they currently have. Talent is raw, untrained ability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calling a person skilled shows respect for the hard work it took to
develop their abilities. Skill is honed, well-practiced ability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a much greater compliment to call someone &lt;em>skilled&lt;/em> than to
call them &amp;ldquo;talented&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It Starts With The In-Ear Mix</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/inearmix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/inearmix/</guid><description>&lt;p>The key to a good musical performance is confidence. Confidence comes from
comfort. Comfort means the musician can clearly hear himself or herself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The in-ear mix is the key to a musician&amp;rsquo;s performance.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The in-ear mix has a few parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-the-headphones">1) The Headphones&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Buy &lt;a href="http://www.shure.com/americas/products/earphones/se-earphones/se215-sound-isolating-earphones">Shure SE215 earbuds&lt;/a>.
$100 is a small amount to spend on a crucial part of
your performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two considerations when buying earbuds: build quality and sound
quality. All Shure earbuds are built to last. The SE215s and above have
removable cables, meaning that you can fix your headphones for the price of a
new cable (around $30) instead of having to buy a whole new pair. The SE215s
have a warm, full, reliable sound. You will not miss anything when you wear
these onstage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The foam tips provide a tight, bass-enhancing seal that blocks
out ambient noise to protect your hearing. Always wear both earbuds. If you leave
one earbud out, you will damage your hearing. One ear is hearing the loud house
mix and the other is hearing the relatively quiet in-ear mix, so you will
naturally turn up the in-ear mix to compensate. You might not suffer hearing loss
in the open ear, but you will suffer hearing loss in the ear with the loud
in-ear mix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read my guide on wearing the Shure SE215s &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1b4MDASpO0i5x4Lvz0Hg9bVW1p-gWygIKmWBJi3Tqkyc/edit?usp=sharing">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-the-mix">2) The Mix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do not turn every channel up. Turn the click track or rhythm-keeping instrument
up, then the lead vocalist, then your own instrument and/or vocal. Everything
else is fluff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take advantage of panning. Pan the vocals, drums, or anything else to the
hard left and right to clear out some space in your in-ear mix. This may sound
abstract, but panning is the key to bringing your in-ear mix to the next level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use the ambient microphone. The ambient microphone is intended
to give the musician an idea of what the house mix sounds like and what the
audience is doing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pull, Not Push</title><link>https://blog.adamvig.com/pushvspull/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/pushvspull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unlock your phone, open all of your social apps, and turn off push
notifications. Only enable push notifications for apps that need instant
responses, such as messages and email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you allow apps to send you push notifications, you give them control over
your schedule. Your attention span is defined by the period in between
interruptions from your phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This approach works better than putting your phone on silent because important
notifications will still come through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reclaim your attention span. &lt;strong>Pull&lt;/strong> information on your own terms instead of
letting apps &lt;strong>push&lt;/strong> the information to you.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>