<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Vigneaux</title>
    <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Vigneaux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.adamvig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On Iterating</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To iterate is to repeat with the intent of reaching a desired goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you know what you want to achieve but you have to create several drafts
along the way, you are iterating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterating can be a process of proving yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situations where money is involved, and the big picture requires a large
purchase, the big picture can be attained through a process of several small
purchases that prove the validity of the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situations where the goal is a dramatic change in the way something is done,
the change can be achieved through a process of proving that the change will be
better. Apply the process in small pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterating can help you see that your ideas are misguided. Instead of going all
in with an unproven idea, the process of iteration forces you to pick your own
idea apart. If it is a good idea, this process has the byproduct of making your
idea succeed. If it is not a good idea, you will see it and change the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To iterate is to prove yourself a little bit at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push Vs. Pull</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consuming information is our new daily activity. It is so easy to do that it
has become a pastime: I read blog posts in waiting rooms, I check Twitter on
the toilet. These are both examples of a “pull.” What I mean is that I, the
user, am voluntarily asking the content provider (a blog, Twitter) for
information. The complement (or opposite, depending on how you look at it) to
this concept of “pull” is (you guessed it) “push.” A push notification is named
as such because the content provider is pushing information to you whether you
like it or not. I make this caveat because in some cases, you may like it: a
text message, a Facebook friend request, or the results of a sports game. But
in other cases, “push” becomes evil: a never-ending group text message, a
Facebook friend asking you to play games with them, or a constant stream of
updates from a sports game. To curb my addiction to information consumption
(specifically from social media with its addiction-fostering tendencies), I
have intentionally limited my “push” activities and turned them into “pull.”
This philosophy has completely changed my phone usage. Not only is my phone now
significantly quieter, but it also has become a way to quickly get up to date on
 any information I missed, then ignore new updates until the next time I am
 ready to “pull.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>