<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Vigneaux</title>
    <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Vigneaux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.adamvig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Posting is Lazy Social Media Strategy</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/lazycrossposting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/lazycrossposting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cross-posting (n): automatically posting content from one social network to
one or more other social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-posting is lazy social media strategy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media users demand content tailored to the audience. Even though the
audience consists of most of the same people between social networks, those
people expect different types of content on each social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instagram:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- low-frequency posts&lt;br /&gt;
- long-form text content is common in the post description&lt;br /&gt;
- focus on the media, not the network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- multimedia posts&lt;br /&gt;
- enough text content to explain the media in the post&lt;br /&gt;
- emphasis on engagement in comments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- high-frequency posts&lt;br /&gt;
- brief text content&lt;br /&gt;
- multimedia posts get the same screen space as text-only posts&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cell Phone Upgrade Strategy</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/cellphoneupgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/cellphoneupgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.adamvig.com/img/post/peoplewhobuythings.gif&#34; alt=&#34;People Who Buy Things Are Suckers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never buy a cell phone new at full price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cell carriers are no longer offering subsidies on new phones. $700 is too much
to spend for that new iPhone. The solution: buy used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying used phones gives you the freedom to buy and sell phones whenever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first phone is your upfront investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put a protective case and screen protector on the phone the moment you take it
out of the box to protect this investment. Protect your investment so you can
sell it for top dollar down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you buy a new phone, sell your current phone to recoup some or all of the
cost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the market price of your current phone before you purchase a new phone to
set a price range for your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where to buy and sell phones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
All three of these sites have buyer protection, so if your phone is defective
you can send it back for a full refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://glyde.com&#34;&gt;Glyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  - Easiest for selling: they ship you a box to put the phone in&lt;br /&gt;
  - Highest fees for selling&lt;br /&gt;
  - Useful indicator of market price&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://swappa.com&#34;&gt;Swappa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  - Low selling fees&lt;br /&gt;
  - Buyer talks directly to seller, not through Swappa&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ebay.com&#34;&gt;Ebay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  - Highest level of risk, but often the best offers&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pull, Not Push</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlock your phone, open all of your social apps, and turn off push
notifications. Only enable push notifications for apps that need instant
responses, such as messages and email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you allow apps to send you push notifications, you give them control over
your schedule. Your attention span is defined by the period in between
interruptions from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach works better than putting your phone on silent because important
notifications will still come through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reclaim your attention span. &lt;strong&gt;Pull&lt;/strong&gt; information on your own terms instead of
letting apps &lt;strong&gt;push&lt;/strong&gt; the information to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Iterating</title>
      <link>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To iterate is to repeat with the intent of reaching a desired goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you know what you want to achieve but you have to create several drafts
along the way, you are iterating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterating can be a process of proving yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situations where money is involved, and the big picture requires a large
purchase, the big picture can be attained through a process of several small
purchases that prove the validity of the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situations where the goal is a dramatic change in the way something is done,
the change can be achieved through a process of proving that the change will be
better. Apply the process in small pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterating can help you see that your ideas are misguided. Instead of going all
in with an unproven idea, the process of iteration forces you to pick your own
idea apart. If it is a good idea, this process has the byproduct of making your
idea succeed. If it is not a good idea, you will see it and change the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To iterate is to prove yourself a little bit at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>