<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Vigneaux</title>
    <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Vigneaux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.adamvig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>External Hard Drive Upgrade (2017)</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/external-hard-drive-upgrade-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/external-hard-drive-upgrade-2017/</guid>
      <description>I need an external hard drive for audiovisual production. I use my external hard drive for two things:
 editing video recording and editing audio  Audio is easy: it does not take much space and does not require high transfer speeds. However, my current drive (a WD My Passport 1TB that I got for free) randomly unmounts, creating huge gaps when recording directly to the drive. The unmounting problem is less apparent when editing video, but is still an annoyance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install LUTs in Premiere Pro CC</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/install-luts-in-premiere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/install-luts-in-premiere/</guid>
      <description>The top search result for &amp;ldquo;How to install LUTs in Premiere Mac&amp;rdquo; is this outdated article.
As it stands now with Premiere Pro CC 2017, the process to install LUTs on a Mac is much simpler than the above article says it is. Instead of having to &amp;ldquo;wash&amp;rdquo; LUTs with SpeedGrade, you can put .cube files directly into the application directory and have them show up in the &amp;ldquo;Looks&amp;rdquo; dropdown of the &amp;ldquo;Creative&amp;rdquo; section of the Lumetri Color effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Sense Security for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/commonsensesecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/commonsensesecurity/</guid>
      <description>1. Use strong, random, unique passwords. Using the same password for every website, regardless of how strong that password is, is dangerous. If your password is exposed at just one of the websites you have signed up for, then that password is compromised everywhere.
Use a password manager. LastPass is free and runs on all platforms; you should try it. It can generate and remember passwords for websites and apps you use, taking the stress and memorization out of security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input Lists and Stage Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/inputliststagediagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/inputliststagediagram/</guid>
      <description>The most important communication that happens ahead of a musical event is in the form of a technical rider.
The technical rider includes specifications for sound, lighting, video, and backline equipment. The key parts of the rider are the input list, which describes all of the audio inputs the band will need, and the stage diagram, which shows the layout of the instruments and performers on stage.
An input list must contain three pieces of information for each input:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skill, Not Talent</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/skillnottalent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/skillnottalent/</guid>
      <description>Talent is natural aptitude.
Skill is hard-earned knowledge and experience.
Calling a person talented implies that they were born with the abilities they currently have. Talent is raw, untrained ability.
Calling a person skilled shows respect for the hard work it took to develop their abilities. Skill is honed, well-practiced ability.
It is a much greater compliment to call someone skilled than to call them &amp;ldquo;talented&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Mac Apps</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/macapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/macapps/</guid>
      <description>InsomniaX: a feature-rich menubar app that allows you to suppress idle sleep and lid sleep on a laptop. Skim: a fast and efficient PDF reader with annotation tools. Display Menu: free with optional $2 pro version upgrade; allows you to adjust display resolution easily, useful to get more space on Retina Macbook displays. Monity: $5, tasteful system monitoring app that displays statistics and info in the Notification Center. Goofy: Facebook messenger app that is essentially a wrapper for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Starts With The In-Ear Mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/inearmix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/inearmix/</guid>
      <description>The key to a good musical performance is confidence. Confidence comes from comfort. Comfort means the musician can clearly hear himself or herself.
The in-ear mix is the key to a musician&amp;rsquo;s performance.
The in-ear mix has a few parts:
1) The Headphones Buy Shure SE215 earbuds. $100 is a small amount to spend on a crucial part of your performance.
There are two considerations when buying earbuds: build quality and sound quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapchat Marketing is Easy!</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/snapchatmarketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/snapchatmarketing/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to social media marketing, Snapchat has a limited feature set but an undeniably huge reach.
Use Geofilters Snapchat Geofilters are graphics that users can overlay on Snapchat photos and videos when they are in certain locations. Geofilters are a great way to create a brand for a specific location such as a city, a neighborhood, or a university.
Snapchat&amp;rsquo;s terms and conditions do not allow the use of logos or trademarks in Geofilters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Posting is Lazy Social Media Strategy</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/lazycrossposting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/lazycrossposting/</guid>
      <description>cross-posting (n): automatically posting content from one social network to one or more other social networks.
 Cross-posting is lazy social media strategy.
Social media users demand content tailored to the audience. Even though the audience consists of most of the same people between social networks, those people expect different types of content on each social network.
Instagram:
- low-frequency posts
- long-form text content is common in the post description</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cell Phone Upgrade Strategy</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/cellphoneupgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/cellphoneupgrade/</guid>
      <description>Never buy a cell phone new at full price.
Cell carriers are no longer offering subsidies on new phones. $700 is too much to spend for that new iPhone. The solution: buy used.
Buying used phones gives you the freedom to buy and sell phones whenever you want.
Your first phone is your upfront investment.
Put a protective case and screen protector on the phone the moment you take it out of the box to protect this investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Iterating</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/oniterating/</guid>
      <description>To iterate is to repeat with the intent of reaching a desired goal.
When you know what you want to achieve but you have to create several drafts along the way, you are iterating.
Iterating can be a process of proving yourself.
In situations where money is involved, and the big picture requires a large purchase, the big picture can be attained through a process of several small purchases that prove the validity of the big picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pull, Not Push</title>
      <link>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adamvig.com/post/pushvspull/</guid>
      <description>Unlock your phone, open all of your social apps, and turn off push notifications. Only enable push notifications for apps that need instant responses, such as messages and email.
When you allow apps to send you push notifications, you give them control over your schedule. Your attention span is defined by the period in between interruptions from your phone.
This approach works better than putting your phone on silent because important notifications will still come through.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>